{
  "trivia": [
    {
      "question": "Where do the cheerleaders wear the 'tiger' rag",
      "answer": "left wrist",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"right wrist",
          "2":"around the neck",
          "3":"left wrist",
          "4":"left ankle"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What clock direction should the tiger paw be turned at?",
      "answer": "1 o'clock",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"12 o'clock",
          "2":"3 o'clock",
          "3":"7 o'clock",
          "4":"1 o'clock"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What famous game day restaurant used to be a gas station?",
      "answer": "Esso Club",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Tiger Town Tarven",
          "2":"Esso Club",
          "3":"TD's of Clemson",
          "4":"Smoking Pig"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the official name of the Clemson Football stadium?",
      "answer": "Memorial Stadium",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Death Valley",
          "2":"Memorial Stadium",
          "3":"Tiger Stadium",
          "4":"SC Stadium"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What color do students and faculty wear on Fridays?",
      "answer": "orange",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"white",
          "2":"purple",
          "3":"orange",
          "4":"black"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "The statue in front of what building can you not read the words on till you graduate?",
      "answer": "Tillman Hall",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Tillman Hall",
          "2":"Kinard Hall",
          "3":"Bracket Hall",
          "4":"Sirrine Hall"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What year was Clemson Founded?",
      "answer": "1889",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"1850",
          "2":"1932",
          "3":"1889",
          "4":"1899"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the current President of the university?",
      "answer": "James P. Clements",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"James P. Clements",
          "2":"Dabo Swinney",
          "3":"Robert H. Jones",
          "4":"Max Allen"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "When year were females able to enroll into Clemson University?",
      "answer": "1962",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"2000",
          "2":"1978",
          "3":"1962",
          "4":"1970"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What did the class of 1915 gift to the University?",
      "answer": "Clemson Ampitheater",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Library Bridge",
          "2":"Clemson Ampitheater",
          "3":"Tiger Statue",
          "4":"The Carillion Bell"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What were Clemson's first school colors?",
      "answer": "red and blue",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"red and blue",
          "2":"orange and purple",
          "3":"orange and blue",
          "4":"white and orange"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What year did Clemson adopt their signature colors orange and purple?",
      "answer": "1896",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"1890",
          "2":"1900",
          "3":"1896",
          "4":"1893"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the student-run paper at Clemson University?",
      "answer": "The Tiger",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"The Roar",
          "2":"Clemson Tiger",
          "3":"The Tiger",
          "4":"The Orange and Purple"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the longest tenured coach?",
      "answer": "Frank Howard",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Frank Howard",
          "2":"Dabo Swinney",
          "3":"John Heisman",
          "4":"John P. Clements"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "How many wins did Frank Howard have?",
      "answer": "165",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"101",
          "2":"65",
          "3":"165",
          "4":"143"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Mascot of Clemson University?",
      "answer": "the tiger",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"baby tiger",
          "2":"the tiger",
          "3":"orange ball",
          "4":"football"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What lake does Clemson University sit next to?",
      "answer": "Lake Hartwell",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Lake Hartwell",
          "2":"Lake Jocasse",
          "3":"Lake Murray",
          "4":"Lake Wateree"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What mountains is Clemson University located in the foothills of??",
      "answer": "Blue Ridge Mountains",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Clemson Mounain",
          "2":"Mauldin Mountain",
          "3":"Blue Ridge Mountains",
          "4":"Walnut Mountains"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What song is sung at the end of every sports event?",
      "answer": "Alma Mater",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Alma Mater",
          "2":"Tiger Rag",
          "3":"Roar",
          "4":"We are the Champions"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the official logo of Clemson University?",
      "answer": "Tiger Paw",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"The Tiger",
          "2":"Tiger Paw",
          "3":"Palmetto Tree",
          "4":"a C"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is one of the nation's largest student run pep rallies??",
      "answer": "Tigerama",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Tigerama",
          "2":"Homecoming",
          "3":"First Friday",
          "4":"Tiger Rally"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the tiger mascot perform after every touchdown?",
      "answer": "Push-ups",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Jumping Jacks",
          "2":"Squats",
          "3":"Push-ups",
          "4":"Pull-ups"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What occurs for 24 hours the day before the Clemson-Carolina rivalry game?",
      "answer": "Banging of a drum in Death Valley",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Banging of a drum in Death Valley",
          "2":"Cocky's Funeral",
          "3":"Prayer Service",
          "4":"Food Preparation"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the C surround on the Clemson ring?",
      "answer": "Palmetto Tree",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Clemson Paw",
          "2":"Outline of South Carolina State",
          "3":"Palmetto Tree",
          "4":"Year you Graduate"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What has been dubbed \"the most exicting 25 seconds in college football\"?",
      "answer": "running down \"The Hill\"",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"running down \"The Hill\"",
          "2":"The Tiger Rag",
          "3":"Cadence Count",
          "4":"First Kick"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "When was the first First Friday Parade held?",
      "answer": "1974",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"1957",
          "2":"1966",
          "3":"1974",
          "4":"1953"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What year did Tigerama start?",
      "answer": "1957",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"1966",
          "2":"1957",
          "3":"1964",
          "4":"1980"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is Howard's Rock named after?",
      "answer": "Frank Howard",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Frank Howard",
          "2":"Dabo Swinney",
          "3":"Howard Frank",
          "4":"John Howard"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "When was Howard's Rock first placed at the top of \"The Hill\"?",
      "answer": "1966",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"1969",
          "2":"1966",
          "3":"1950",
          "4":"1975"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What do the football players rub before every home game?",
      "answer": "Howard's Rock",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Dabo's Head",
          "2":"Memorial Stadium",
          "3":"The paw in front of the stadium",
          "4":"Howard's Rock"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What year did the \"Tiger Rag\" began playing?",
      "answer": "1942",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"1942",
          "2":"1956",
          "3":"1977",
          "4":"1930"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "When was the first meeting between Clemson and Alabama?",
      "answer": "1900",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"1910",
          "2":"2015",
          "3":"1900",
          "4":"1948"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What years did Clemson win the Football National Championship?",
      "answer": "1981, 2016, 2018",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"1981, 2016, 2018",
          "2":"2016, 2018",
          "3":"1981, 2017, 2019",
          "4":"none"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What was Clemson University originally named?",
      "answer": "Clemson Agricultural College",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Military Clemson College",
          "2":"Clemson  Academy",
          "3":"Argicultural South Carolina College",
          "4":"Clemson Agricultural College"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What years did John Heisman coach Clemson?",
      "answer": "1900-1903",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"1901-1910",
          "2":"1950-1955",
          "3":"1900-1903",
          "4":"1903-1904"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the field the soccer team plays on?",
      "answer": "Riggs Field",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Noonan Field",
          "2":"Riggs Field",
          "3":"Ibrahim Stadium",
          "4":"Historic Field"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where do the Clemson basketball team play their home games?",
      "answer": "LittleJohn Coliseum",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"LittleJohn Coliseum",
          "2":"Death Coliseum",
          "3":"Brownell Coliseum",
          "4":"Tiger Coliseum"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Where state is Clemson University in?",
      "answer": "South Carolina",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"North Carolina",
          "2":"South Carolina",
          "3":"Georgia",
          "4":"Florida"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What team did Clemson beat in the 1981 National Championship?",
      "answer": "Nebraska",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Alabama",
          "2":"LSU",
          "3":"Ohio State",
          "4":"Nebraska"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the Clemson Tigers' fight song?",
      "answer": "Tiger Rag",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Alma Mater",
          "2":"Tiger Rag",
          "3":"Candence Count",
          "4":"Clemson Chant"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What conference is Clemson in?",
      "answer": "ACC",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"ACC",
          "2":"SEC",
          "3":"Pac-12",
          "4":"Big Ten"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Clemson's rivalry with the South Carolina Gamecocks is known as what?",
      "answer": "The Battle of the Palmetto State",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"The South Carolina Game",
          "2":"USC vs Clemson",
          "3":"Chicken vs Tiger",
          "4":"The Battle of the Palmetto State"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the nickname of the Clemson Tigers marching band?",
      "answer": "Tiger Band",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"The Roar",
          "2":"Tiger Children",
          "3":"Tiger Band",
          "4":"The Band"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What do fans bring with them as a tradition when attending away games?",
      "answer": "$2 dollar bills stamped with Tiger Paws",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Tiger Rag",
          "2":"$2 dollar bills stamped with Tiger Paws",
          "3":"Hat",
          "4":"A Tiger Stuff Animal"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first Clemson Tiger to be inducted into the College Football Hall of Fame?",
      "answer": "John Heisman",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"John Heisman",
          "2":"C.J. Spiller",
          "3":"Donnel Woolford",
          "4":"Sammy Watkins"
        }

      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is said to occur if you take a stroll with your loved one done Lovers' Lane?",
      "answer": "That you will marry each other",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"That you will never break up",
          "2":"nothing",
          "3":"That you will break up with each other",
          "4":"That you will marry each other"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you begin the Cadence Count?",
      "answer": "C-L-E-M in Cadence Count",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"Cadence Let's go",
          "2":"1-2-3-4",
          "3":"C-L-E-M in Cadence Count",
          "4":"Clemson!"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What color is worn for Military Appreciation Day?",
      "answer": "Purple",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1":"White",
          "2":"Orange",
          "3":"Purple",
          "4":"Black"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What do many different organizations build on Bowman during homecoming week?",
      "answer": "Floats",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1": "Floats",
          "2": "Houses",
          "3":"Tiger Replicas",
          "4":"Statues"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a Clemson Tradition on Black Friday",
      "answer": "Cocky's Funeral",
      "choices": [
        {
          "1": "Go shopping",
          "2": "Cocky's Funeral",
          "3": "Eat Chicken",
          "4": "Blood Bowl"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}